# Byron Buckley | linkedin.com/in/byronbuckley

# Capability Statement

I am a proficient frontend engineer with recent experience creating intuitive user experiences for financial applications and e-commerce websites. Over the last 5+ years I have honed my skills working with React, TypeScript, VueJS and Carbon Design System to develop state driven UIs and applications.

# **Employment History**

# **Frontend Engineer**

#### **IGNITION ADVICE** | Apr 2021 - Present

As a front-end engineer at Ignition, I collaborate with the product and design team in an Agile workflow to complete tasks. Previous activities include:

- Authored or extended 32 reusable React components over the last 12 months, per JIRA.
- Improved the interaction design of the low-code financial journey builder.
- Consumed inhouse API's that drive the financial advice journeys on the front-end.
- Developed a template editor with Handlebars and Web Components enabling the sales team to rapidly generate new client proposals.
- Championed deeper adoption of the Carbon Design System and socialized patterns for documenting components with Storybook.
- Tested components thoroughly using Jest, React Testing Library, and contributed to E2E tests with Cypress.
- Performed comparative analysis to drive translation management software selection.

### Frontend Engineer

## KOALA FURNITURE | Jan 2018 - Sep 2020

Supported the growth and maintenance of Koala Furniture's ecommerce experience as they grew to a valuation of \$500 million. Key contributions include conducting website experimentation, implementing content infrastructure, developing reusable product detail page (PDP) templates, and creating scalable components.

#### **Product Growth**

- Built the Bed Base PDP, which highlighted the need for reusable templates and a headless CMS.
- Collaborated with the engineering team to develop a robust PDP template using Contentful, reducing new PDP development time from ~6 weeks to 5-7 days with minimal developer interaction.
- Enabled Koala to expand from 4 bedroom products to 20 products across the bedroom, living, and dining room categories.

### Experimentation

Supported data-driven decisions by ideating and implementing experiments using Optimizely and Visual Web Optimizer.

#### **Sales & Promotions**

Co-architected e-commerce theme definition for site-wide promotions, reducing the effort required for custom theming in key parts of the site during promotions. Ultimately this enabled us to be agile enough to launch sales early, or pivot to change promotions post-launch.

## Contract UI Developer

#### CANTILEVER | Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

Cantilever is a boutique digital agency that creates quality websites and web applications. As a Frontend Developer, I was primarily tasked with responsive template development and integration with ExpressionEngine, Shopify and Craft CMS. Project work includes:

- Cantilever Retainers Single page template development with Jekyll.
- The Four Holy Gospels Microsite and mobile app built with Jekyll.
- **Fizzics** Shopify theming, and development.
- Handi Lift Template development, SVG animation.

#### Contract Web Developer

## THE HERO CO | Nov 2015 - Aug 2016

The Hero Co is a digital marketing company based in Texas and California, USA. My primary activities revolved around using PHP & JavaScript to integrate various websites with third-party email, commerce and analytics services. Other duties included:

- Developing and extending internal/outsourced HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript assets based on set specifications
- Cross browser development and testing
- Coordinating end-to-end tests with Lead Developer and QA team
- Running tests on a sequence of pages to check validity of analytics, conversion tracking pixels, etc. and document test results
- Identifying limitations and deficiencies in existing systems and providing and/or implementing solutions to deficiencies
- Writing, updating and maintaining operational procedures in company knowledge base
- Providing advice, guidance and expertise to team members

# Contract UI Developer

# KRAFTED By Us (KBU) | Apr 2015 - Jun 2015

KBU is a web agency based in Santa Monica, CA. During my contract tenure I was primarily tasked with responsive template development for client websites running Expression Engine or Craft CMS. While I worked with HTML and SCSS; CMS and JS development was handled by the Lead Developer. Project work includes:

- Solemates: www.thesolemates.com
- Genova Homepage for A/B Test: www.genovaseafood.com
- Chicken of the Sea | Mapbox Implementation

## UI Developer

#### MEDULLAN INC. | May 2014 - Apr 2015

Headquartered in Cambridge, MA; Medullan is a digital healthcare solutions firm that provides solutions for clients across the healthcare continuum. In my brief time at this company I've contributed to a few projects with my usual gusto for doing things the right way. Projects include:

- **Humana** responsibilities included developing front-end markup from the provided Axure and InVision mockups as the designers iterated through concepts based on the user research tests. I was also tasked with ensuring the markup delivered adhered to the client's style guide and existing codebase. Other activities included coordinating the four-member developer team. Stack: Harp Web Server + LESS + EJS + Heroku.
- PrescriptionIQ (http://prescriptioniq.com/) new product marketing website built with Bootstrap, Jekyll, SASS and Bower. Also responsible for styling the accompanying responsive AngularJS app.

- UI/UX Framework Standards and Best Practices internal tool to standardize FED and get projects running quickly; built with Bootstrap and Jekyll.
- BlueCross BlueShield FEP (<a href="https://www.fepblue.org/web/guest/myblue">https://www.fepblue.org/web/guest/myblue</a>) a responsive AngularJS project that I joined briefly, I was tasked with maintenance work, UI bug fixing, and minor feature implementation.

## **UI** Developer

#### REALDECOY INC. | Mar 2011 - May 2014

Headquartered in Ottawa, Canada; RealDecoy is a consultancy that specializes in providing enterprise search solutions for e-commerce websites using Oracle's Endeca. I was responsible for the construction and maintenance of web pages for both internal and external projects. I worked with the UX team to maintain the integrity of the visual and interaction designs during development and/or implementation. Project tasks include markup development for client implementation, as well as UI development for Java and ASP.NET web and mobile-web applications.

## **Business Support Officer**

## CAPITAL & CREDIT FINANCIAL GROUP (CCFG) | Apr 2008 – Mar 2011

As Business Support Officer, my activities resided in the domains of Software Developer and Webmaster for a multisite Drupal installation. As a Developer, I was responsible for developing and maintaining applications and modules for the group's foreign exchange remittance systems as well its core banking system.

# Education

- University of Baltimore Graduate Certificate in Information Design (Fall 2013)
  - User Research Methods
  - o Information Architecture
  - Interaction and Interface Design
  - o Humans, Computers and Cognition
- Northern Caribbean University B.Sc. Information Science (Fall 2007)